Achroo Batta











PROFILE

An IT professional with 16+ years of IT experience in Managing and Solutioning design, Implementation, architecting IT/Cloud Solutions keeping with built-in Security posture. Well versed with Agile & Waterfall Methodologies, Automation Frameworks, CI-CD Pipelines, Lift-Shift Strategy, Cloud Security Architecture, Solutions along with excellent Leadership abilities. Firm believer in continuous learning along with the growth mindset

Some of my 'key' technical cert hunts below ...

- 4 x Azure Certified [AZ-900, AZ-104, AZ-400 and SC-900]
- 1 x AWS Certified [AWS Solution Architect Associate]
- 1 x Kubernetes [Certified Kubernetes Administrator]
- Hashicorp Terraform Associate Certified
- **Certified Scrum Master**

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming
 - Infrastructure As Code using Azure Bicep for Azure, Terraform for AWS, and Azure
 - o Python, PowerShell
- Tools
 - Jira, Docker, Kubernetes, Azure Boards, Bitbucket, GitHub, Azure DevOps, Jenkins, Confluence etc..
 - Azure, AWS Products and Services,
- Security Frameworks
 - information security and privacy frameworks (ISO 27001:2022)

CAREER HISTORY

AVANADE Consulting - Sydney [Sr Consultant, App Security]

Mar 2022 - present

Key Projects, Responsibilities and Achievements:

- Infrastructure & Security Technical Lead Involved in Data Migration project for Commonwealth Bank [CFS] to implement a solution to migrate, transform and extract Terabytes of data from CBA network to CFS Azure Cloud Space. My role is to
 - Design of Ci-CD pipeline and GitHub branching Strategy following Microsoft's best practices
 - Creation of Low-level design documents and attend review meetings with key stakeholders.
 - Attending Biweekly meetings with Client program managers about status updates and drive other key discussions.
 - Manage and segregate work among team members.
 - Participate in Daily sprint activities and attend review meetings.
 - Implemented solutions using Azure Bicep and Azure DevOps pipeline for Azure resources like VNets, Subnets, RT, NSGs, VMs, Storage Account, Key Vaults etc.,
 - Received SuperHero Award for managing and implementing solution.
 - Mentored & Lead 10 Junior project members for the successful project execution.
- Solution Architect Involved in solutioning of 'DevOps pipeline Optimization' for Mater [Catholic, Non-profit Organization] using DevSecOps strategy to bring onto the Uniform platform across the organization.
 - o Meeting with Technical key stakeholders of different business units to understand their workflows and existing build strategies.
 - Reviewed their existing Azure Cloud footprint and come up with re-organizing the DevOps project hierarchy.
 - o Prepared High Level Design and Solution document for new DevOps roadmap.
 - CI-CD Uplift recommendations for a full DevSecOps alignment
 - Prepared Estimation, Pricing and Resourcing model for implementation of project using Avanade internal Tool.
 - Budget forecasts, Cost considerations and efficiency metrics to demonstrate ROI implications to Head Cloud and DevOps operation of Mater.
 - Mentored and walkthrough of technical design/solution to implementation team of 5 members.
- Technical Security Manager involved in 'Complex Active Directory Advisory Security Assessment' for RioTinto client under their On-premises Window servers' environment.
 - Involved in discussion with Architect and Client Project Manager to understand the scope and timelines of project.
 - o Drive program which involves vulnerability scanning and implementing fix using AD Scheduled tasks.
 - Seek approvals from key stakeholders for the implementation phase which involves other Security Engineers and Identify SMEs to be part of that project execution.
 - Preparation of Progress Dashboards and sending reports to clients.

- Played a role which involves effective communication, project Tracking and impediments resolver during course of project.
- Driving internal scrum meeting with team of 5
- o Presented project milestones and key achievement to client.
- Infrastructure Lead Implementation of POC for modernization of Commonwealth Bank [CFS] legacy Dot net application. My role
 comprises of: -
 - Understand the requirement of POCs by attending discussions/meetings with client key stakeholder and Senior Architect
 - o Implemented showstopper items of the purposed solution in 20 days.
 - o Documented solution implementation and test results.
 - Design and Documented Branching and CICD strategy
 - o Presented solution to Client Key stakeholders and receive accolades for achieving in short time span.
- Infrastructure Lead [Internal Project] Successfully executed the 'Asset Building & Pipeline creation Project' with a team of 5
 to develop Terraform modules for all the Azure Services which enables a central repository for the Avanade COE objectives to benefit
 engineers as a reference point moving forward for any engineering needs. This helps in young talent enablement.

Global Payments-Formerly TSYS [Technical Manager]

Nov 2010 - Jan 2022

Worked on diverse set of roles starting from Software Engineer to Technical manager on variety of projects ranging from legacy applications to modernization of applications for **US/UK Banking clients** for TS2 products.

Key Responsibilities:

- Working closely with development team for deployment fixes.
- Build CI/CD pipelines for Gradle/java spring boot projects using shell/python scripts.
- Setting up K8s cluster using KOPS/EKS in dev/qa regions for DI teams.
- Maintaining and apply patches on in house K8s Clusters.
- Upgrading YAML configurations for deployments, pods.
- Migration of infrastructure to Cloud using Terraform.
- Attending/driving scrum processes like Sprint planning, Sprint review and other ceremonies.
- · Managing and communicating with stakeholders.
- Participation in DR activities.
- Build CI/CD pipelines using AWS Code Commit, Code Pipeline and Code Build.
- Written infrastructure as code using BuildSpec.yaml for Lambda functions, Dynamodb, API gateway, S3 invokes cloud-form.
- Implemented serverless architecture on AWS for server-based application.
- Distribution of work and deliveries in team of 10.

Achievements:

- Ramp up of team from 3 to 10 by gaining and building trust with client.
- Refactoring of server-based solution to serverless solution led to cost savings.
- POCs on using ARGO CD for K8s projects rather than traditional CICD process.
- Build technical solutions for multiple projects and delivered them successfully with Zero Defects.
- Implemented multiple Initiatives towards coding standards, code coverage.
- · Asset building for young talent enablement.
- Coached and trained junior team members on new tech stacks like AWS, Kubernetes.

DXC Technology-Formerly CSC [Programmer Analyst]

Jul 2007 - Nov 2010

Worked as Onsite Coordinator and programmer analyst on implementation of compliance on acquirer side of **Barclaycard**, **Northampton**, **UK** in Credit Card Domain.

Key Responsibilities:

- Worked as Onsite coordinator to get requirements from Enterprise Architect and served as a bridge between onsite and
 offshore team.
- Worked on CSD preparation, addition of new fields in file layout, code changes, unit test case preparation and unit testing.
- Problems detected by end user are raised in quality centre.
- My role was to analyse, recreate, bug fixing and delivery document preparation for high, medium, and low priority problems.
- Implemented compliance related changes in Association/Interchange/Schema related code changes.

Achievements:

- Appointed as a DP Coordinator
- Got nominated for internal reward program for automation of manual activities using REXX
- Independently handled Level1 defects.

EDUCATION